all right let's do some why we came here
uh okay uh say Sawa you guys ready say
Sawa Z no I mean projected okay good uh
this is talking about the meaning of
loong okay how to do loong and it says
uh uh say sa means when you eat okay
when you study Lo
and then when you eat
breakfast
uh you are taking care of your body
which already belongs to other
people okay your body is the property of
other people already if you commit to
bodh Safa activity if you commit to bodh
safa's way of life then you gave your
body
already uh to other people it doesn't
belong to you anymore
okay if you really decide to follow
bhis path then uh you already gave up
your body and your and your heart okay
you already gave up your your life to
other people so
um so then it's a funny thing then it's
your
responsibility to take care of other
people's property and eat a good
breakfast you see and take care of your
mind with the goodn night
club okay why it doesn't belong to you
anymore okay it's like you borrow your
friend's
car uh you borrowed your friend's car
you cannot uh make it dirty and give it
B okay you have to take care of it take
good care of the car so
now when you reach this part in the L
rim and you decide okay this bu S I
think sounds pretty good to me I would
like to be a bodh sappa then I have news
for you you don't own the car
anymore your time and your body is owned
by people okay by other people and now a
strange
responsibility you know gesla loves
cinnamon rolls I even built a cafe to
serve the cinnamon
rolls so I could eat them and uh but
now uh I have to have these stupid green
drinks
look I have to take care of my body uh
because I don't own it now uh other
people own it the world owns my body
okay it's very
beautiful Jin says Jin Sin Sin means
finished you gave it already to other
people okay it's not your body anymore
you can't eat crap anymore you don't
have the right you can't put bad
gasoline in the car okay it's not your
car anymore if if you decide to do buddy
serer you know so bud sappa is not like
blah blah blah I'm B sappa okay eat
green drink have green drinks no more
cinnamon rolls
oh
okay do your yoga like John Bry like
hone those guys embarrass me they they
actually practice every day um I think
so uh Sam Jen doing
D lud means I have to take good care of
this body because it doesn't belong to
me anymore I gave it I made a commitment
to give it to everybody's like G you're
gonna te di away You're gonna give me
bud yes but then I own your
body and you have to take good care of
it you have to exercise it every day you
have to do your yoga you have to feed it
well because then it belongs to the
world it doesn't belong to you anymore
okay and by the way um don't be scared
and don't
hesitate uh when you give your body to
everybody it feels right it's like
giving half your income to other poor
people it feels good you feel you feel
like ah finally I'm doing the right
thing you know finally I'm
really sharing my body with other people
that's it's the right thing to do okay
it's it's the right thing to do to share
your money with other people I bought
this stupid ring today
$9,000 okay my wife doesn't know
yet uh let me tell her when she's in a
good mood okay like give her a good
dinner honey I'm G to cook Indian food
she's like oh then I say I bought a
$9,000 ring you know she's like
okay uh then 3,000 goes to ACI okay and
there's a long story uh
yeah long story about this this ring
quickly uh a guy in England an old man
told his wife he's he's going to buy a
metal
detective and she said why and he said
I'm going to go out to the cow pasture
and look for you know ancient things and
she's like like waste of money waste of
time you know then uh his I'll show you
his picture it's really funny he's
really old like old rusty guy you know
and then he he got the metal detector he
went out he found this ring uh under the
ground it's a thousand years old and it
has a diamond in it and it has French
ancient French writing probably some war
or some we don't know how it got to
England and it says keep the faith with
me like I keep the faith with you in
inside in ancient French and uh so we
decided to to make a ring like that we
we made a ring based on that and it has
a diamond the the original has a diamond
crystal because at that time they don't
know how to cut diamond but they know a
diamond is powerful it can scratch all
things so we made a copy my wife and I
got one each we keep the faith with the
ring and uh we we each bought one we
bought it in two years cuz we couldn't
buy two in one year and uh so we both
wear one now and I encourage you if you
if you want to make a donation to ACI
ACI uh commitment is that the teachings
are free okay and uh I went to United
Airlines in New
York and I said I'm from ACI and they
saidwell so what
and I said we don't charge anything we
give all the teachings for free you know
and then they said why you tell us that
I said therefore I need free airplane
ticket uh to go to Kyoto you know like
that and they're like shut up you we
don't do
that so unfortunately we we still have
to fly here I did try I promise I asked
them and they said no very impolite me
and uh so we still need some money to
pay for
travel this staff keep people have a bad
habit they keep
eating and uh then the food we we went
to the restaurant we said we are ACI we
teach for free just give us dinner for
free and they also threw us out so uh we
do need some money to to to give the
teachers for free we need airplanes we
need food we need so anyway if you buy a
ring it's good luck to have the diamond
I love to have the extra diamond for my
meditation it's very powerful if you
don't buy this one or you don't buy the
other one I'm going to keep bugging you
to wear a diamond okay we gave away
diamonds last night to all the
uh DC
Sim all of them God free Diamond left
night uh and uh it's important to have a
on okay
so
anyway uh even if and this is beautiful
he says even you
do Diamond W practice secretly in your
room it's similar to eating food okay
you have a
responsibility to feed your body well
because you gave it away way already and
you have a responsibility to feed your
mind the most valuable teachings which
is Diamond way it's very beautiful okay
and it's not for you it's not for you
it's for other people okay it's like put
the best gasoline in the car that
belongs to your friend okay and keep it
super clean take care of the body with
healthy food I hate green
ah
so I want to keep the body going as long
as possible by the way it starts to wear
out my age everything falls apart what
do old people talk Ellie what do we talk
about when we get together you got any
new doctors
yeah okay so take care of your
body uh and while you take care of it
think this doesn't belong to me I borrow
this body this belongs to the whole
human race it's not my oh the whole
living race this body belongs to them
and for the mind it's not green drink
it's Diamond way for the mind you should
feed it Diamond way why it's not your
mind you gave away the mind you said I
give my body and mind to other people
you don't it doesn't belong to you
anymore if you're holding it and you're
what do you call caretaker of this body
and you're the caretaker of this
mind then it's your responsibility to
put the sweetest things in the mind
because it doesn't belong to you anymore
okay so what's the sweetest thing ask
John Connie Ellie G say Rosa all those
guys ask them to teach you Diamond way
okay put the best things in your heart
uh because it's not your heart anymore
that heart belongs to everybody else
okay cool all right My teacher asked me
a beautiful question uh at this point in
the L
room he said uh do you give your body to
all beings I say yes I mean I try and
then do you give your heart to all
beings yes okay then you have to eat
well and you have to put sweet things in
your mind like deep deep teachings in
your mind and then he he had a beautiful
thing which I'll share with
you uh he said are you one of all
beings then I'm like
hm yeah I guess I am you know and he
said you're a stockholder in your body
and your heart you're also one of the
stockholders you know there there's many
shares of this stock called
Michael everybody has a share every
living creature on this planet 100
billion creatures on this planet
everyone has a share in gashi Michael
and gashi Michael has a share one little
share in gashi Michael's heart and gashi
Michael's mind it's gishi Michael's
responsibility to take care of gishi
Michael for gesi
Michael so if you become a Buddha that's
the best way to help gim Michael so you
have responsibility to take care of gim
Michael okay cool nice right
yeah uh you guys ready is it lined up
is it lined up Ricardo you guys is it
ready ready to
go ah a couple minutes they're real film
people couple minut they have a mantra
couple minutes okay couple minutes all
right uh next paragraph
me good me Pena if a doctor tries by the
way each one of these is like uh what do
you call it
add it's just jumping from one beautiful
thing to another but they're very
beautiful it's like trying to go to the
lou in Paris right you guys Tatiana Mr
Tatiana uh you go to the loop there's so
many beautiful things to see and you get
actually
headache you have to stop actually and
take a coffee or something because it's
too too much Beauty you know so that's
the load okay there's 22
different Crazy Beautiful advices here
okay in the seventh part of the seven
part modu okay
uh if a doctor tries to help you okay if
a doctor tries to give you medicine M
pen means if it doesn't help
you chak means um
blood leting so in the old days they
will uh bleed you to take out the Bad
Blood okay that was a medical treatment
in the old days and there's two ways to
do it you can uh put a hole in the vein
or you get a leech you get a worm a
special worm and a the old doctors were
called leeches leech givers and they put
this this uh worm on your arm and they
suck the blood and supposed to be they
suck the bad blood out so tarwa means
the old system of blood we call blood
leing in English SE means uh a Marx
abusan uh and they burn your hand or
they burn your skull they burn your head
and uh I was a translator for the doll
Lamas two doctors they are the two
greatest doctors in Tibet I translated
for about uh five years for them
whenever they come to America I will
translate for them and uh I watch them
do this to people they do acupuncture
they call
cup it's a Golden Needle and then they
WRA cotton around it I watched them do
it to a rich lady in New York it was fun
because she was freaked out and first
they put the needles and then they put
the cotton and then they light the
cotton and it burns the
the needle gets super hot and it doesn't
hurt it it affects your prer it goes
deep into your prer you know so if the
me if the doctor gets desperate if they
see the medicine doesn't work they will
bleed bleed you or they will Mark Theus
they will burn
you there's a super
antidote that if the doctor cannot cure
your
heart they can use the secret antidote
what's it
call yeah exchanging Stu other okay if
the doctor sees you are
incurable your heart is too cold your
heart will never change then they use
the ultimate medicine the ultimate
medical treatment which is
lo which is
D
okay treat other people like they have
equal right to happiness and then give
your happiness to them
okay
UHA is a is a difficult word in tibetan
and it means
uh it serves the purpose like if you
don't have a hammer uh you can use a
heavy pipe or something go CH it you can
be in a pinch in a difficult situation
you can use a a stone to to to drive a
nail it's called
Cupa and uh he says D
picture
picture yes okay uh in in American
English we call Swiss Army knife so the
Swiss Switzerland Army invented a
special knife for their soldiers and it
has everything you need everything is
there okay uh it can do a hundred
different things they're very cool uh
they're very very cool you can buy them
and if you do camping a lot uh Swiss
army knife is like heaven it's like the
most amazing thing okay you can eat with
it you can cut with it
you can fat with
it it can do anything there's a little
saw you can saw things okay it's a
beautiful thing what does okay $100 $100
now everyone's wake
up
$100 what's this knife
represent ah don't say it be wise just
hold up your hand get the money who
who's the who's the who's where's Tim
Al
Al wait you have to choose
somebody thank you g uh I think this uh
knife uh represent the uh all kinds of
uh how to say the uh we are have a bi uh
body CH and we can uh provide many kinds
of uh method to help uh different kinds
people good Lo yeah 100 thank you
yeah okay so coach coach means one knife
fits all needs loj fits all these you
don't have to learn a thousand different
things uh one knife can do everything
you guys
ready all
right so you have a you have a
responsibility once you gave your body
to other people once you gave your mind
to other people uh you have a
responsibility before you do anything
and after you do anything okay
everything you do during the
day before you do it you have one
responsibility and after you do it you
have another responsibility okay uh
what's
[Music]
before it means uh any uh important
activity you do during the day after you
commit to Moo after you commit to bodh
right uh then you do some project like
you're doing a
magazine or something like that okay or
you have some big job at your work or
some big family
project then you in if your body
sappa you have to pause for one minute
before you do it okay like before you go
to work or before you do your yoga or
and you have to say
I'm doing this for everybody I'm doing
this for everybody owns my body
everybody Owns My
Heart and today I'm going to work for
eight hours or something and I'm going
to do the work for
everybody I'm doing this for everybody
so Kong cha means when you start your
day you have to pause and say I'm doing
this for all the stockholders of gashi
Michael gishi Michael is just one
stockholder okay and I'm doing this for
all the stockholders okay guess what you
have to do after you finish when you're
coming home from
work dedicate okay dedicate coffee
meditation okay I did a good job today I
worked for eight hours or something I'm
going to take my rest now with my book
club good
night by the way you got to be tough on
yourself okay and and you know don't do
it don't decide right away take some
time okay but when you're ready talk to
Rosa Rosa you want to stand up she's got
the bags okay
uh all
[Music]
right uh don't don't just jump okay
think about it first if you break it
it's a very bad karma
it's better not to do it if you're not
sure you can do it then wait okay then
wait but if you decide to do it uh then
talk to Rosa and get get your bag and
your lock and by the way you need the
log trust me uh if you don't have a loog
at
10:15 uh you will open the case and you
will you know you just start watching a
movie again you know you the problem
with Korea soap up is they never tell
you the ending it's always like next
time we're going to find out should they
kiss each other or not and you're gonna
definitely open the case Okay so talk to
Rosa get the SP but but make a decision
to try you might want to try a a time
limit okay you might want to try a time
limit okay so talk to Rosa or you can
talk to Lindsay where's Lindsay can you
stand up yeah Lindsay she's working on
it
okay uh all
right how what time I have to stop Tim
or Al Al
They seven is 19
right okay all right
uh okay I'll take questions in five
minutes okay
uh kungar so before you do something big
after you commit to about the supper
think about why you're doing it pause
think about why you're doing it and then
when you finish put it in the bank put
it in the bank it means dedicated to
other people okay today I spent uh many
hours teaching and now I'm going to go
rest take my rest eat dinner watch a
movie before 10
o'clock and
uh maybe and and that's okay it doesn't
disturb sleep and then and then I'm
going to go to bed and I dedicate the
whole day to to other people okay to my
owners to my
stockholders in the Michael Roach stock
okay all
right so two things to do every thing
every major thing you do before and
after all right uh
next
paragraph
I like this word
say the first two words here
say uh there's a beautiful custom in the
monastery I told some of you uh there's
you
know how do you get into the gashi
course you know how do you get into the
monastery and there's a process it's
quite strict you know uh if you want to
join the gashi course you have to have a
sponsor someone has to agree to be your
sponsor and then uh it has to be a
usually it's another G who's already a g
and then they will take you to the
monastery
office and they'll say he's my guy so my
teacher I I spent eight years with him
then he said okay I will sponsor you and
he took me to the monastery uh office
and he said I I I'm his
sponsor I I promise he will
behave I promise he won't embarrass the
sa I promise he will follow the rules I
promise he will try to be a gishe you
know and they have a big book you know
and they you stay they they like a very
serious ceremony and then they say are
you sure and my teachers say yes I'm
sure and they said okay we're going to
write his name in the book and he's like
it's okay go ahead yeah it's okay then
I'm scared you know and then they say
maku
maku kelang knows Ru means the water
that came out of the corpse that my my
name in tibetan means dead body water Ro
Marco Ru yes okay okay uh
Marco then they
say they close the book
and CH and you're supposed to say k CH
say k CH you have to hit something you
can hit sty Kido
[Laughter]
cha H Kido cha means now you're one of
us now you're one of us okay and what
the literal meaning is key means happy
and Duke means uh suffer K cha means uh
when the S is happy we're all happy when
the SAS suffer we all suffer together
when in the French they have a those
three guys Three Musketeers all all for
one and one for all it's the same thing
all for one and one for all you know uh
if we eat today we eat together if we go
hungry today we go hungry together and
that's a real sa that's K okay so I love
this word okay we should do it
right
means means whether you're having a good
day or a bad day okay whether or whether
okay okay keep your Lo okay I'm having a
good day
Lo how share it with other people God
look at how beautiful the trees are in
in this season the Autumn season and
then in the
Sakura wow look at this trees you know
like share the joy with other
people and if there's Co and then put
your mask on and share the
suffering uh with other people that's
loo
okay
then he gives two
examples he says
people's people's commitment to the
bodis ideal is destroyed by two things
what they're too happy or they're too
sad okay people's commitment to to act
like a bu saer can get destroyed by two
things too happy and two that okay
what's the
happy you get a big position at
work or Jaa you get some money you get
some big money or you get some big
position and it destroys your
Dharma okay too much money and too much
success and you're like I don't need
Dharma I'm Superman you know I'm so
handsome I'm so rich I have such a big
position I don't need loj okay so
sometimes success will destroy
your okay on the Other
Extreme some people get into a terrible
situation like a war or or they they get
a big enemy at work or or something like
that you get cancer something like that
then shwa you lose your bod staa
commitment you're so suffering you're so
thinking about your pain oh I got cancer
you know oh I lost my job oh I I I I
lost my position you know I don't have
money then so happy too much happiness
can destroy your
Lo and too much problems can destroy
loto okay so when those two things
happen you have to be careful when you
get famous when things are going well
when you get a lot of money be
careful and then when you get divorced
you know you have problem with your kids
and your kids failed the college exam
okay then you have to watch be careful
with your low jum don't lose your low
jum practice okay don't get sad and lose
your low jum practice don't lose your
faith because some big problem happened
that's could be a seed from 10,000 years
ago we don't know
okay I asked a doctor recently I said
what caus cancer he laughed he said you
know you touch plastic once in your life
and that's it now I'm like what you got
to touch plastic you know and he says
well that's the it's just a it's the
odds you know it's how many odds like
that means don't lose your practice it's
much shter one means don't let too much
success and don't let too much problems
destroy your body self of practice okay
be careful when you're in the middle
everything's okay when you get really
rich or famous be careful okay be
careful with those Netflix
guys okay and then uh when you have a
disaster uh your wife leaves you or you
know your house burns down
you lose your business at something
just tell your mind to shut up it every
everything comes back sooner or later
everything's come back don't there's no
big disaster like that don't lose your
body stle practice okay all right well
I'm going to mark it
there stop what's the date s
eight okay and uh we'll take questions
uh Tim
or who choose the
questions we have
about 15 minutes something I guess
right
correct
okay
[Music]
when
sh join ch slow take a time yeah um so I
have a friend um he or she had a little
caddy a cat and then she uh this cat had
like serious disease and it is it's
really suffering for it for the cats and
then my friend was thinking like to have
like a treatment a we of getting her to
die easily which is called the in
intha oh
eia yeahia but this is also a way of
like killing life right so what does uh
my friend can do to really help her to
become more comfortable in being in such
a bad situation yeah good
question uh oh yeah and the one part
story uh share uh his friend like uh her
friend like telling the pen story before
the cat like maybe pass away okay good
okay good
uh this question comes many times and I
had a dog uh I inherited a dog
unwillingly uh someone asked me to take
care of the dog and then they never came
back and uh did you know Theo yeah cute
dog and my wife and I we had this
discussion many times first his hips got
bad he couldn't use his legs his back
legs and then he lost his
eyesight and then he lost his
hearing and he would drag his body in
the corner and get stuck in the corner
of the house and then he will cry and it
break your heart it was break your heart
he you know and he can't see anything he
can't hear anything he's just dragging
his legs and uh when he pee pees at
night I have to carry him outside and um
you know he will cry and I'll pick him
up and carry him outside and it was
difficult and we also had this
conversation you know
uh should should mercy killing right
should we give him special medicine and
he will die
quietly and cuz his life is terrible his
and his teeth are gone
also and they charge $800 to take out
his teeth you know how America this is
America so uh we talk and we talk and we
talk and and I asked my teacher about it
he had the same problem because he loves
dogs and he takes care of dogs and if
the person is
a real Buddhist strong strong Buddhist
if they understand Buddhism if they
really understand
Buddhism uh they understand one thing to
be a
blind deaf
crippled
toothless crying dog in in a human's
house is better than what comes
after okay
99% what comes after is much much worse
than that okay 99% chance is
99% you know what happens after he dies
is much much the the the chances
99 there's some terrible pain after that
so real Buddhist if you really really
study a long time meditate a long time
see other
worlds uh you will not kill an
animal uh because what's coming is worse
much much worse so uh you will try to
keep them alive as long as possible even
they are
suffering uh and you will say mantras to
them and and you will try to put the
seeds in their mind for future give them
something to take with them uh to the
next place okay now if you're not a
Buddhist and you don't understand those
things and or you're not sure about what
will
happen and all you can see is the animal
is suffering then you should you should
end the animal's life okay so understand
the answer if you have deep wisdom deep
training and you understand the
99 then keep the animal alive as long as
you can and my
teacher he washed the the dog lose all
the hair lose their legs everything he
still keep them alive and he he he takes
care of them all day like that and
uh and if you really understand but if
you don't
understand it's a good deed to kill them
okay understand no if you if you're not
sure or you're not strongly trained and
this dog is really
suffering uh you should you should put
them to sleep you should do it because
what you understand what you know you
should act on that you should do that
okay so my wife put him to sleep okay
she put him to sleep and I'm like that's
your decision you know so I think if
your motivation is good and you really
want to help them and you really want to
serve them uh that's a good seat okay
that's a good seed so you have to you
have to use your wisdom okay not an easy
answer not an easy
question one
more
hi um I have a question I have a Blog
and question question uh people um I'm
ask people what is the purpose of their
life and they say dancing singing enjoy
thems making money um having sex eating
having
children um and um don't say they won't
get out of
sansara and um they're right that really
gives pleasure all all this um all these
and
um
um uh in in these points you can find
meaning of life really people can find
uh meaning of life and it's hard to uh
for me uh to explain them uh they will
lose all of this when they
die so my questions are these benefits
traps of samsara or gifts because they
can derail
I didn'ts it's traps of samsara or gifts
oh okay got it yeah yeah or gifts okay
good yes because it can awaken him or me
good good okay good
question
uh I think the answer is
practical you know what will help people
what's the best way to help people and
uh if you go if someone come to you and
say how do I get a cute boyfriend or how
do I get some great sex you know what's
the plant how do I plant the seeds for
great sex or great drugs or you know for
the best best wine how do I plant those
things you know and then you say oh we
are
Buddhist no sex no
wine no
fun just die very good you know
then I guarantee they will run away
okay so uh the real wise Buddhist like
my teacher I learn everything from my
teacher I learned Tibetan language I
learned sutras but I also learned
practical practical he's practical among
all the llamas that I met he's practical
and he sent me to business you know and
he he he will say that someone say how
can I have better sex and he say ah you
have to plant the seed you know and uh
and this is also Lord Buddha's uh
system uh you always start at the
person's level you always start at that
level okay as long as it's not illegal
or or destructive someone say what's the
Buddhist way to make the best bomb or
you know like that you have to say go
away you know I I I don't have that you
know but if it's if it's not destructive
like it's good sex or or better wine or
how to have a good boyfriend how to find
a good boyfriend like that then Lord
Buddha's
system is to start at their level always
start at their level you know say God I
got this four-step system for good sex
you
know you know they're like wow I like
that religion you know and uh I got four
stepsister for good wine or or something
like that and this is Lord Buddha's
system and that's why we have four
schools of Buddhism it's very famous
very famous so Lord Buddha is
practical Lord Buddha hooked the fish
then squeeze the fish okay so first you
know promise them
good STX good money
success you can call it
DCI and
uh you know and uh get them interest get
their interest you know and then when
they get cancer they are ready they know
the system and then you can teach the
real thing you know then you can teach
the real thing so uh everything has a
the proper place and every every human
desire can be used by a skillful teacher
to bring the student up okay so uh we
don't judge people we don't say come on
don't be stupid you know you're going to
die yeah he like well I'm 20 I want to
have some good sex before I die okay
let's plant that right see okay so uh
that's fine okay and don't be shy don't
be shy about it my teacher gives some
amazing hot
answers uh and I'm like ribete you been
a monk since you were 5 years old and
you're telling this lady how to have
great sex he's like got to tell you know
and uh you know he did he never tasted
alcohol in his whole life I was lucky
because I went to Princeton first I
tried everything you know I experienced
everything I think it makes me a month
you know uh so I have all those
experience so go to their level help
them uh at that level and then stay with
them through months and years of their
life and the then the serious questions
will start to come oh my my mom got
cancer or you know uh there's a war in
my country you know then the the serious
questions will come but first hook them
uh in the system and let them have
success and uh and and then you will be
there when they need you and and that's
the idea hook them when they are healthy
young
beautiful sex having sex and then uh
stay with them and later they will need
you later they will ask you the more
serious questions okay good okay thank
you
yeah